好啦
Okay.
听着  我要搬过去了
Listen, I'm moving out,
以后你就得负责交租的事了
so you're in charge of paying the rent.
-行  什么时候要缴  -一号
- Right. When's it due? - First of the month.
每个月都得交吗
And that's every month?
不是  你想住的月分才要缴
No, just the months you want to live here.
这是电话费
Okay, here's the phone bill.
上帝啊
Oh, my God!
那是我们的电话号码
That's our phone number.
听着  是我突然决定
Now look, I know I kinda sprung
说搬就搬的
this whole me-moving-out-on-you thing,
让我先帮忙你分摊一段时间吧
So why don't I just-why don't I just cover you for a while?
不  不必了
No-no! No way!
乔伊·崔比安尼不再...
Joey Tribbiani does not take charity...
接受施舍
...anymore.
-这不是施舍  乔伊  -不行  别再说了
- lt's not charity, Joe. - No! Forget it! Okay?
谢谢  但我不想再拿你的钱了
I mean thanks, but I'm done taking money from you.
我可以养活自己
All right, I can take care of myself.
-还有什么  说吧  -好吧
- Now, what's next? Come on. - Okay
好  这是电费
Here's the electric bill.
-用个电要这么多钱啊  -对
- This is how much we pay for electric? - Well, yeah.
那其他的帐单之后再看吧
So we'll do the rest of the bills later, then?
那乔伊也得搬出去吗
So is Joey going to have to give up the apartment?
希望不用
No, I hope not!
我想给他钱  但是他不收
I tried to offer him money, but he wouldn't take it.
你觉得他需要多少
Well, how much do you think he needs?
我想一千五应该够他活几个月
I figure that $1,500 would cover him for a few months, y'know?
但我得骗他收下
...but I have to trick him into taking it
-免得伤害他的自尊  -没错
- so I don't hurt his pride. - Yeah.
你怎么不雇他当演员
Why don't you hire him as an actor?
你可以叫他扮装演短剧
You could have him dress up
穿个小裙  怎样都行
and put on skits whenever you want.
那样对自尊"确实"有帮助
Well, that would help the pride thing.
哇  大美人一个
Wow, you look great!
明天要不要搬来跟我住
Do you wanna move in with me tomorrow?
-好  -很好
- Okay. - Okay.
你们女生今晚要做什么
So, what do you girls have planned for tonight?
与其难过
Well, instead of being sad
今晚过后我就要和瑞秋分离
that tonight is my last night together with Rachel
我们觉得不如去吃饭庆祝...
We thought we'd go out to dinner and celebrate the fact that
瑞秋马上要搬去跟菲比住
Rachel's moving in with Phoebe.
-还有我的生日  -今天不是你的生日
- And also my birthday. - lt's not your birthday.
这样讲好恶劣
What a mean thing to say!
换我  就绝不会戳破你
I'd never tell you it wasn't your birthday.
那你们男生有什么节目吗
So you guys have anything planned for the big last night?
与其一起出去玩
Instead of just hanging out,
我们决定什么也不做
we figure we'd do nothing.
今晚是尼克队首战,
Knicks' season opener tonight.
我以为你们会想来我家看呢
I thought maybe you guys would come over and watch it.
不知道呢  罗斯
I don't know, Ross.
不想听你又说为了成为古生物学家
not if you're gonna talk about how you gave up a career in basketball
而放弃打球的事
to become a paleontologist.
我的确是放弃了打球人生
I did give up a career in basketball
去当古生物学家
to become a paleontologist!
-菲比  我在想...  -你居然还没换衣服
- Pheebs, I was wondering...  - You're not dressed yet?
我们十五分钟后就要去玩了
We're supposed to start having fun in 15 minutes!
而且早一分钟都不行
And clearly, not a minute sooner.
瑞秋  你都打包好了  对吧
Rachel, you are packed though right,
拜托告诉我  你已经打包好了
I mean please tell me you're packed?
那是当然  莫妮卡  你别紧张
Of course I'm packed. Monica, relax.
我只是让菲比给我今晚的衣着点意见
I just wanted to ask Phoebe her opinion on what I should wear tonight.
天啊  我真是一刻也不得闲
My God, I can't get a minute of peace.
我的天
Oh, my God!
莫妮卡会宰了你
Monica's just gonna kill you.
嗯  我知道
Yeah, I know.
你穿这样倒是蛮适合惨死的
What you're wearing is fine for that.
瑞秋  我要借...
Rachel, I need to borrow
你还没打包好
You're not packed!
你根本一点都没打包
You're not packed even a little bit!
惊喜吧
Surprise!
什么
What?
你别发飙  是这样的
Don't get mad, because this is what happened.
我开始打包
So I started packing,
然后意识到  我在干嘛
then I realized, "What am I doing?"
我最不会打包了  对吧
I am lousy at packing, right?
但你最爱打包了
But you love packing!
所以做为我的临别赠礼...
So as a gift to you on our last night....
我可以当总指挥
I'll be coordinator!
我的天  对不起  我没帮你准备礼物
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry. I didn't get you anything.
大家都要帮忙  好吗
Okay, look everybody has to help! Okay?
菲比  你可以帮忙吧
Phoebe You can help, can't you?
我有约了
I have plans.
-你是跟我们有约  -没错
- You have plans with us. - That's right.
好吧  钱德勒可以弄纸箱
All right, Chandler can make boxes,
罗斯封箱  乔伊搬东西
Ross can wrap and Joey can lift.
-菲比  去通知男生让他们帮忙  -好
- Now Phoebe, go tell the guys they have to help out! - Okay.
天啊  谢谢你
My God, thank you!
快逃  莫妮卡要叫你们收拾东西
Hurry! Monica's gonna make you pack!
她把工作都分好了
She's got jobs for everyone!
我是躲不掉了  你们快逃吧
Now, it's too late for me, but save yourselves!
搬家公司十一个小时后会来
Okay, the movers will be here in 11 hours.
瑞秋还没打包
Rachel hasn't packed.
每个人都得帮忙
Now, everybody has to help.
-钱德勒  你先从...  - 我和乔伊有约了
- Chandler, we're gonna start with...  - I have plans with Joey.
你不是说你们要闲着嘛
You said you were doing nothing.
是啊  最后一次一起闲着呢
Yes, but for the last time.
好吧  罗斯...
Okay fine, now Ross...
-我没办法帮忙  -为什么
- Oh, but-but I can't do it. - Why not?
-因为本要来  对吧  -因为本要来了
- Don't you have Ben? - Because I have Ben!
都快8点了  他都快上床了
It's almost 8 o'clock, it's almost past his bedtime.
-他在哪里  -他去参加晚宴了
- Where is he? - He's at a dinner party.
他真的要来吗  我可是看得见你家喔
Is he's really coming? Because I can see into your apartment.
当然是真的
Of course he is.
干嘛  难道我会拿儿子当藉口吗
What, do you think I'd just use my son as-as an excuse?
你把我当成哪种爸爸了
What kind of father do you think I am?
好吧  对不起
All right. Sorry.
我得做个本的人偶了
I gotta go make a fake Ben.
来了
Here it is.
室友时代最后的披萨
Our last pizzas together as roommates.
我不知道你会买披萨  我叫了中国菜
Oh, I wish I’d know you were going to do that, I ordered Chinese.
没关系
Well, that's okay.
其实这样蛮好的
Hey, actually in a way it's kinda nice.
我们最后的两人晚餐
You know, our last dinner together.
我带我祖先的食物
Me, bringing the food of my ancestors...
而你  也带你祖先的食物
...you, the food of yours!
乔伊  最后一晚了  我有个奇怪的想法
Say, Joe, I had a strange idea of what we could do for our last night.
我们玩几盘足球机  赌钱如何
What do you say we play a little uh, football for money?
你疯啦
Are you crazy?
自我九七年伤后复出  你就没赢过我一次
You haven't beaten me since my injury-plagued '97 season.
-你送钱我还比较快  -是啊
- lt'd be easier to give me your money. - Yes, it would.
赌五十元如何
What do you say to $50?
-来吧  -好  开赛
- Ok, you're on. - Okay, let's play.
世纪之战  意大利对...
The big game. ltaly versus...
中国队  大概吧
...China, apparently.
看  是直排轮鞋
Look, it's the Rollerblades.
我的天
Oh, God!
-记得我们什么时候买的吗  -不记得
- You remember when we got these? - No.
那你应该不在
I guess you weren't there.
喂  我们说过要开心的
You guys, we said we were gonna have fun.
别这样  记不记得那次...
Come on. Hey, remember the time....
你们不记得吗
You don't remember?
对不起  菲比  要搬走我真的很难过
I'm sorry Pheebs, I guess I'm just really sad that I'm leaving.
我会很想你
I'm gonna miss you so much.
其实不必这么难过
This doesn't have to be so sad, though, you know?
或许你们应该停止
Maybe instead of just thinking about
怀念对方的美好
how much you're gonna miss each other,
转而想想对方的不好
you should like think of the things you're not gonna miss.
我觉得没有
I don't think there's anything.
总会有一两样啊
Come on, there's gotta be something.
没有  她太完美了
No, she's perfect.
我想起一个了
I have one.
很好  你先说
Okay, Great! you can go first.
我绝对不会想念
I guess I'm not gonna miss the fact...
你从来不准我移动留言笔
...that you're never allowed to move the phone pen.
说得好  莫妮卡  你有吗
That's a good one. Okay, Monica, anything?
瑞秋会移动留言笔吗
You know, does Rachel move the phone pen?
有时候啦
Sometimes.
其实每次都会
Always, actually.
好  这就对了  这样不是好多了
Okay, good. There you go. Doesn't everyone feel better?
不只是留言笔
Not just the phone pen.
我老是收不到留言
I never get my messages.
你收到过啊
You get your messages.
我真的觉得
Yeah, well I don't think it really counts
得从睡着在沙发上的你的手背上
if you have to read them off the back of your hand
自己读留言不算
after you fall asleep on the couch.
那你是没接到谁的留言  钱德勒吗
So you missed a message from who? Chandler?
还是你妈
Or your mom?
还是钱德勒
Or Chandler?
还是你妈
Or your mom?
太好了  成功了  没人难过了
Great, it worked! No one's sad!
万岁  我又赢了
Yeah! I win again!
你已经欠我五百了
That's 500 bucks you owe me!
天啊  五百元
Man! Five hundred dollars.
能买多少电啊  对吧
That is a lot of electricity, huh?
我得买点吃的了
I gotta buy some food.
给我翻本的机会  最终骤死战
Give me a chance to win my money back. Sudden death...
一球...一千
...one goal, $ 1000.
-来真的吗  -当然
- You serious? - Oh, yes!
好吧
Okay.
-准备欠我钱吧  -好
- Get ready to owe me. - Okay.
来吧  准备好了吗
Okay, Here we go. Ready?
不  不  不  不
No! No! No! No!
不...可能有人能打败我
No...one can beat me!
看吧  这就是为什么
See? That's why only the little fake men
只有小假人可以出脚
are supposed to do the kicking.
你好
Hello?
罗斯啊  看吧  还有别人会打给我
Hi, Ross. See, other people call me!
你老哥  了不起
Oh, your brother. Score!
怎样
What's up?
我跟本在一起
Oh, I'm just over here with Ben.
想跟你问个好
Thought we'd say hi.
-叫他听  -本  跟莫妮卡姑姑打招呼
- Put him on. - Ben, say hi to Aunt Monica.
看来他现在不想说话
I guess he doesn't feel like talking right now.
不过他在笑哦
He's smiling, though.
好  待会再聊
Okay, talk to you later.
我觉得你们难过那会儿比较好
I am thinking it was better when you guys were sad.
记得这双直排轮鞋吗
Hey, remember the rollerblades?
你知道我还不会想念什么吗
You know what else I won't miss?
我是莫妮卡
I'm Monica.
我一天刷十七次马桶
I wash the toilets 1 7 times a day,
即使有人在上  也照刷不误
even if people are on it!
我是瑞秋  我的毛衣太紧了吗
Hi, I'm Rachel. ls my sweater too tight?
不会吗  那我得洗一洗让它缩水
No? I'd better wash it and shrink it!
我是莫妮卡
I'm Monica.
从来没有有趣的人留言给我
I never get messages from interesting people, ever!
我有打给她啊
I call her.
天啊  我爱罗斯  我恨罗斯
"Oh, my God! I love Ross. I hate Ross.
我爱罗斯  我恨罗斯
I love Ross. I hate Ross!"
我的天  我交不到男朋友
My God! I can't find a boyfriend.
干脆杀到对面去
So I guess I’ll just stumble across the hall
看到谁就上谁
and sleep with the first guy I find there!
对  如果想赶去餐厅订位
Yeah, we should get a move on
就得快点了
if we want to make those dinner reservations.
修不好了吗
Still broken?
真是烂透了
It sucks, man.
你在这里的最后一晚
Your last night here,
我却失去了人生中两样最重要的东西
and I lose the two most important things in my life:
足球台
The foosball table...
和五百元
...and $500.
有别的办法可以把钱赢回去
But there are other ways to win back your money.
要不要玩二十一点
How about a little uh, a little Blackjack?
我不在行
Nah, not my game.
好吧  要不这样
Okay, uh, how about, how about-y'know what?
我们玩个新游戏
We can play a new game.
-新游戏  很好玩的  -叫什么名字
- A new game, it's fun. - What's it called?
杯牌
Cups.
-我不会玩杯牌  -我教你
- I don't know how to play... - I'll teach you.
来嘛  简单又好玩
Come on, come on. lt's really easy and really fun.
-好吧  -好  拿牌
- All right. - Okay. Here you go.
我有两张皮蛋  你呢
I have two queens. What do you have?
-2和5  -你赢了  五十元
- A 2 and a 5. - You win! Fifty dollars!
-真的吗  -没错  再一轮
- Really? - Oh, yeah. Let's play again. Ready?
-你是什么牌  -四和九
- What have you got? - 4 and a 9.
不会吧
You're kidding, right?
-怎么了  -那是满杯
- No. Why? - That's a full cup!
我真是杯牌高手啊
Damn, I am good at Cups!
我不要跟她说话
I'm not talking to her.
总得有人先开口
Well, one of you has to take the first step...
这个人应该是你
And it should be you,
因为她要搬走  她比较难过
because she's the one who's leaving. lt's harder for her.
也许吧...
Maybe you're right.
但她嘲笑我的留言笔
But she made fun of my phone pen!
我知道  我也觉得很过分
I know. I took it hard too.
瑞秋  刚才的事我很...
Listen Rachel, I feel bad about what happened- -
-你在干什么  -把东西拿出来
- What are you doing? - I'm unpacking.
什么
What?
我不搬了  这幅画挂得正吗
I'm not moving. ls that picture straight?
歪了十万八千里
It needs to go about 20 blocks to the left.
你知道吗  是你要作出改变
Hey, y'know what? You're the one who wants this big change
跟钱德勒同居
and to move in with Chandler!
你才应该走  为什么要我走
You should be the one to go! Why do I have to leave?
因为这是我的房子
lt's my apartment!
它也是我的  还有呢
lt's mine too! What else you got?
还有就是你要搬出去
How about: You're moving!
-不  不  不  -搬  搬  搬
- No, no, no, no! - Yes, yes, yes!
莫妮卡
Okay, Monica...
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
我们应该帮你打包
We should be packing you!
你们谈得怎样
Hey, how you guys doing?
很好  莫妮卡要搬走
Great. Monica's moving.
我才没有
I am not!
是吗  那为什么你的东西都在这个箱子里
Really? How come all your stuff is in this box?
好  女士们  女士们
Okay, you guys, you guys,
我知道这是怎么回事了
I think I know what's going on here, okay.
女士们  停
You guys? Stop!
你们是假装生气
I know that you're acting mad
来掩饰内心分离的痛苦
because you think that it'll make it easier to leave
其实内心深处  你们还是很难过
But deep down, you're really sad.
最最深处
Deep, deep down.
不  菲比  我很生气
No, Phoebe, I am mad!
最最最深处
Well deep, deep deep down.
我就是很生气
I'm just mad.
那就继续追吧
Then keep running.
你赢了
You win!
-你是什么牌  -不重要
- What did you have? - It doesn't matter because nothing beats
因为三和六最大
...a three and a six.
那叫"D罩杯"
That, my friend, is "D Cup."
你目前为止赢了多少
Okay, how much have you won so far?
-哇  七百  -不是正好七百吧
- Wow, 700. - Not 700 exactly?
是啊
Yeah
加倍
Double it.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yes.
在杯牌里  一旦赢到正好七百
In Cups, once you get $ 700,
就得自动加倍
you have to double it.
-真的吗  -规则又不是我订的
- Really? - Hey. I didn't make up the rules.
拿到加码奖金后
Okay, so now, after you receive the doubling bonus,
你可以再拿一张牌
you get one card.
那张牌有可能值一百元
That one card could be worth $100,
让你总共赢得一千五
which brings your total to $ 1500.
别太兴奋
Don't get too excited,
除非你拿到...
that won't happen unless you get the...
不会吧
No way!
这是最后一箱衣服
This is the last box of your clothes.
标注就是"脑子有病吗"
I'm just gonna label it  What were you thinking?
有意思  因为我正想到对面
Funny, cause I was just gonna go across the hall
在钱德勒身上写一样的话
and write that on Chandler.
两位  不是我想雪上加霜
Hey you guys, I don't mean to make things worse, but...
但我不想跟瑞秋住了
...l don't wanna live with Rachel anymore.
-什么  -什么
- What?! - What?!
你们对对方好坏
You're so mean to each other.
我不想跟瑞秋不欢而散
I don't wanna end up like that with Rachel.
我还是喜欢你
I still like you.
没关系  菲比  因为我不搬了
Well, Phoebe, hat's fine because I'm not moving.
菲比  你一定要收留她
Phoebe, you gotta take her.
我是说了很多她的坏话
You know I-I-I said some really bad stuff about her,
但瑞秋也有一些
But you know Rachel has some good qualities
好室友的特质
that make her a good roommate.
真的吗  比如说呢  莫妮卡
Oh really? Like what Monica?
你知道她有几千双靴子吧
You know she has 147,000 pairs of boots...
真是个好的开始
Oh yeah, good start Mon.
她会借给你穿
She lets you borrow them.
然后你再用你的大脚
Yeah, and you stretch them out
把它撑大
with your big old clown feet.
你想睡路边吗
Do you wanna live outside?
天气开始在转冷了哦
Because it's getting cold!
她有一大堆购物目录
She gets tons of catalogs
她会把我会喜欢的部分折起来
and she'll fold down the pages of the things she thinks that I'd like.
还有呢
What else?
我洗澡时
When I take a shower...
她会在镜子上留言给我
...she leaves me notes on the mirror.
那倒是  这个没错
yeah, I do. I do do that.
真好
That's nice.
我喜欢浴室里有东西阅读
I like having things to read in the bathroom.
我在沙发上看书看到睡着
When I fall asleep on the couch after reading...
她会帮我盖毯子
...she covers me over with a blanket.
我不希望你冷到
Well, you know, I don't want you to be cold.
当我说我要跟钱德勒同居时
And when I told her I was gonna move in with Chandler...
她非常支持我
...she was really supportive.
你真好
You were so great.
让我无后顾之忧
You made it so easy.
现在你要走了
And now you have to leave.
我得跟一个男生住了
And I have to live with a boy!
不会有事的
It's gonna be fine.
瑞秋  我真希望你赶快搬进来
Okay Rachel, now I can't wait to live with you!
你知道我们还应该怎么做吗
And you know what we should do?
让莫妮卡也搬过来  我们仨一起住
Bring Monica and then we could all live there together!
一定会很好玩
We'll have so much fun!
但是亲爱的  她要跟钱德勒一起住了
But honey, I think she's moving in with Chandler.
也对
Oh, that's right.
你还是要跟他住吗
You're still set on that?
应该吧
Kind of.
我的天
Oh, my God!
你好
Hello.
莫妮卡  打包顺利吗
Hey Mon, how's the packing going?
本吗  他很好  他就在...妈呀
Ben? He's fine. He's right--  Oh, my God!
把头从衣服里伸出来什么
Get your head out of your shirt there, son!
对  是南瓜  我过去帮忙
Yeah, it's a pumpkin. I'll come pack.
-怎么了  -罗斯和我帮忙她们打包
- What's wrong? - Ross and I were helping girls pack...
在休息时
...took a little break.
我跟他玩杯牌输了一千五
I lost $ 1500 to him in Cups!
玩杯牌怎么会输
How did you lose at Cups?
跟你输的方式一样
The same way you lost!
我先拿到老K和Q
I started out with the king and the queen.
结果罗斯拿到2和3
Bam! Ross gets a 2 and a 3.
然后我拿到J和老K
Then I get a jack and a king.
结果罗斯拿到4和5
Boom! Ross gets a 4 and 5.
罗斯拿到满杯  D罩杯
Even Ross was getting the Cup card, the D Cup...
和自动加码
...the sitting- down bonus.
我连半副杯牌都凑不到  什么都没有
I didn't even get half a cup! Nothing!
天啊
Oh, man!
他之前也没玩过  我发现重要的一件事
He never played before either. You know what I think?
我发现玩杯牌都靠新手的手气
I think beginner's luck is very important in Cups!
好  我们再玩一把  就一把
All right, let's play one more hand. One more hand.
不要  我一毛钱也输不起了
No, no more! I cannot lose another dime.
我是说真的
I'm serious this time.
事实上
In fact, look.
我要送你一样东西
I wanna give you something, okay?
现在先送给你
Let me give it to you now
免得我为了赌债拿去当
before I pawn it for Cups money.
我要把大白狗送给你
I want you to have the big, white dog...
作为感谢
as a kinda of a, y'know, thank you
你这些年来的照顾
for being such a great roommate.
我不能收这个雕像  那是你的最爱
I can't take the big white dog. You love it.
他不是雕像  他是活的
It's "him." Not "it."
要是我跟你买呢
What if I bought it from you, you know?
你可以以合理的价格卖给我
Then your nice gesture would be giving it to me at a reasonable price.
一千五如何
Say $ 1500?
等一下  我知道你想干嘛了
Wait a second. I see what you're trying to do here.
你又想塞钱给我
You're trying to give me money again!
我什么时候塞钱给你了
When did I try to give you money?
之前看帐单的时候
Before, over there,with the bills!
你想施舍我  我说不要
You tried to give me charity, I said no,
你也就算了  对吧
you dropped it, okay?
然后我们开心度过最后一晚
We had a nice last night together.
然后我们说笑  赌钱
We had some fun, we gambled,
谁也没塞钱给谁
nobody tried to give anybody any money.
结果现在你突然又想来这套
Now out of the blue, you start with the charity thing again!
我只是想帮助你
I'm trying to help you out, okay?
我只想确定你的生活没问题
I wanna make sure that you would be okay.
我会没问题的  钱德勒  听着
I will be okay. Look Chandler,
你不能老觉得
You gotta get it out of your head
我无法照顾自己
that I can't take care of myself, okay?
我不会怀念你借钱给我
Look, I'm not gonna miss you helping me out with money.
我唯一会怀念的
The only thing I'm gonna miss...
就是你
...is you.
现在还有这只狗
And now the dog.
-到了打电话给我  好吗  -好
- Call me when you get there, okay? - Okay.
我真的会很想你
I'm really gonna miss you.
钥匙要还你
I have your key.
拿去  谢谢
- Here you go. - Thanks.
天啊  我们真傻
God, this is silly.
再过几小时又能见面了嘛
I'll see you in a couple of hours.
房子  再见
Bye, house.
-再见  -再见
- Byebye. - Bye.
-她真的走了  -我知道
- She really left. - I know.
-谢谢你  -不客气  室友
- Thank you. - No problem, roomie.
-我可以问你一个问题吗  -当然可以
- Can I ask you a question? - Sure.
那只狗怎么会在这里
What the hell is that dog doing here?
我捏造了杯牌游戏  好塞钱给乔伊
I invented the game of Cups as a way to give Joey money.
-现在你想把钱要回去  -没错
- And now you want that money back? - Exactly.
钱德勒  你以为我是白痴吗
Chandler, what kind of idiot do you take me for?
没有那种牌  那是我捏造的
It's not a real game. I made it up.
很遗撼你的钱没了
I'm sorry you lost your money.
但我赢得光明正大
But I won it fair and square.
游戏是假的
At a fake game!
如果你想赢一点回去
If you wanna try to make some of it back...
我愿意陪你玩
...I'd be glad to play you for it.
但我必须警告你
But I should warn you.
我是杯牌高手
I am very good at Cups.
好  你上次玩
Okay, I assume the saucer card came up
有出现杯盘牌吧
when you played last.
没有
No
看看这次会不会出现
Let's see if it comes up this time.